Emanuel Ruben Piore Papers ca.1918-1986 Mss.Ms.Coll.80
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Subject files, 1930-1986; 32 boxes; 16 linear feet (Box Series I: 1-32)
  - Handler, Philip, 1917- -- His Tenure as President of the National Academy of Sciences, 1981-1982; 4 folders
    - Folder 3, 1982; 11 items
    - Folder 4, 1982; 16 items
  - Harris, Patricia, 1924-1985, 1984; 3 items
  - Harvard University, 1972-1984; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1972-1979; 20 items
    - Folder 2, 1980-1984; 22 items
  - Harvard University. Visiting Committee, 1957-1971; 5 folders
    - Folder 1, 1957-1962; 17 items
    - Folder 2, 1963; 17 items
    - Folder 3, 1964; 14 items
    - Folder 4, 1965-1969; 24 items
    - Folder 5, 1970-1971; 23 items
  - Harvey Mudd College, 1960-1971; 12 items
  - Havoens, B. L. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1973 June 19; 1 item
  - Health Advancement, inc., 1972-1978; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1972; 19 items
    - Folder 2, 1973-1975; 18 items
    - Folder 3, 1977-1978; 2 items
  - Health Research Council of the City of New York, 1961-1968; 20 items
  - Hertz, Roy, 1984; 2 items
  - Hesburgh, Theodore Martin, 1917-, 1977; 6 items
  - Hewlett, William -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1985 March 13; 1 item
  - Hill, Albert G., 1979; 2 items
  - History of the Directors of Industrial Reseach -- TMs, 1 item
  - Hobbins, James M., 1983; 3 items
  - Hofmann, Valentine, 1973; 3 items
  - Hofstra University, 1983-1984; 14 items
  - Holtzman, Wayne H. -- Computer-Assisted Instruction in the United States: Past, Present, and Future, 1977; 1 item
  - Hone, -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1972 September 9; 1 item
  - Hunt, James B., 1937-, 1977-1985; 9 items
  - Hunter College. Institute of Health Sciences, 1970; 4 items
  - Hyatt Regency Cambridge, 1984; 4 items
  - Ingle, Dwight Joyce, 1907-, 1972; 1 item
  - Institut de la vie, 1972-1976; 31 items
  - Institute for Advanced Study (Princeton, N.J.), 1978-1979; 5 items
  - Institute for Defense Analyses., 1959-1971; 34 items
  - Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, 1955-1984; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1955-1971; 32 items
      Includes group photograph of Piore and others at the Joint Technical Advisory Committee meeting. Removed to Series V.
    - Folder 2, 1973-1984; 19 items
  - Intercontinental Book and Publishing in Deutschland, 1982-1983; 5 items
  - International Conference on High-Energy Accelerators (12th: 1983: Batavia, Illinois), 3 items
  - International Conference on the Unity of the Sciences, 1981; 22 items
  - International Rescue Committee, inc. -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1985 September 5; 1 item
  - Insurance policies, 1955-1971; 2 folders
    - Folder 1
    - Folder 2
  - Invitations, 1971; 29 items
  - Israel, 1968-1971; 46 items
  - ITNR Advisory Corporation S.A., 1976; 1 item
  - Japan, 1983 October; 1 item
  - Jason, Leonard, 1966-1971; 30 items
  - Jennings, Edward H. -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000., 1981 July 21; 1 item
  - Jewett, Frank Baldwin, 1917-, 1976; 5 items
  - J. M. Rubin and Sons, inc. -- TDS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 September 28; 1 item
  - Johansgatan, Karl -- TNS to Piore, Emanual Ruben, 1908-2000, 1981 February 20; 1 item
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1976; 2 items
  - Johns Hopkins University -- Policy Advisory Committee, 1975; 53 items
  - Johnson, Agatha -- TLS from Piore, Emanual Ruben, 1908-2000, 1973 August 1; 1 item
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973., 1961-1963; 4 items
  - Jones, Gilbert E. -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1976 May 25; 1 item
  - Journal of computational physics., 1964-1968; 16 items
  - Kac, Mark, 1984; 2 items
  - Kahn, Robert F., 1917-, n.d.; 1 item
    Resume.
  - Kapitsa, P. L. (Petr Leonidovich), 1894- -- The Bernal Lecture, 1976: Scientific and social approaches for the solution of global problems., 1977; 1 item
  - Kaplan, Joseph, 1986; 3 items
  - Katcher, David A., 1976; 2 items
  - Kaya, Seiji, 1898-, 1975-1981; 7 items
  - Kelman, Steven, 1985; 4 items
  - Keynan, Alex, 1921-, 1973-1979; 4 items
  - Kheel, Theodore Woodrow., 1979-1980; 2 items
  - Kibbee, Robert J., 1980-1982; 2 items
  - Kiley, Robert R. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1983 October 11; 1 item
  - Killian, James Rhyne, 1904-, 1973; 2 items
  - King, Seth S. -- TMs Cy Test Finds I.O.'s Can Be Lifted for Children of Retarded, 1972 July 17; 1 item
  - Kline, Sidney, 1982-1983; 2 items
  - Kochen, Manfred, 1975-1976; 4 items
  - Kortchmar, Emil, 1984; 2 items
  - Laboratory Data Control, inc., 1970-1971; 36 items
  - Lamport, Bernard, 1929-, 1985; 2 items
  - Land, Edwin Herbert, 1909- -- On the Proper Properties of the Permeable Membrane between Research and Engineering., 1972; 1 item
  - Landon, Ned, 1979; 2 items
  - Lankford, John -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1984 December 1; 1 item
  - Lauritsen, Charles Charles, 1892-1968, 1971; 3 items
  - Lawless, William J., 1982-1983; 2 items
  - Levi, Edward Hirsch, 1911- -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1975 February 24; 1 item
  - Libby, Leona Marshall, 1919-, 1983; 4 items
  - Library of Congress, 1974 September 18; 1 item
  - Lin, Robert I., 1983; 3 items
  - Lipsky, Karl, 1971; 2 items
  - Lists, 2 folders
    Various membership lists.
  - LogEtronics, inc., 1968-1985; 5 items
  - Logsdon, John M., 1937-, 1980; 2 items
  - Lord and Taylor Benefit, 1985; 3 items
  - Loveless, Mary -- TNS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 February 1; 1 item
  - Loweth, Hugh, 1976; 2 items
  - Lundquist, Stig, 1925-, 1 item
  - Mahoney, Margaret, 1924-, 1984; 2 items
  - Majestic, 1981; 3 items
  - Malone, Thomas, 1980 May 12; 1 item
  - Manfred Sakel Institute, 1971; 3 items
  - Manhattan Cable TV, 1985; 3 items
  - Marconi International Fellowship, 1977; 2 items
  - Marcy, H. T., 1974; 2 items
  - Marine Biological Laboratory (Woods Hole, Mass.), 1955-1984; 6 folders
    - Folder 1, 1955-1971; 15 items
    - Folder 2, 1973-1974; 18 items
    - Folder 3, 1976-1977; 28 items
    - Folder 4, 1978-1981; 16 items
    - Folder 5, 1982; 7 items
    - Folder 6, 1983-1984; 15 items
  - Marine Biological Laboratory (Woods Hole, Mass.) -- Nominating Committee, 1973-1974; 15 items
  - Mario Negri Institute Foundation, inc., 1975; 6 items
  - Marshak, Robert Eugene, 1916-, 1983; 2 items
  - Marshall, Burke, 1922- -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1982 July 15; 1 item
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1955-1983; 7 folders
    - Folder 1, 1955-1967; 22 items
    - Folder 2, 1968-1971; 40 items
    - Folder 3, 1972-1977; 34 items
    - Folder 4, 1979-1984; 16 items
    - Health Sciences and Technology -- Folder 5, 1972; 6 items
    - Visiting Committee for the Department of Physics -- Folder 6, 1971-1974; 20 items
    - Visiting Committee for the Department of Physics -- Folder 7, 1975-1983; 17 items
  - Mayor's Commission for Science and Technology, 1984-1985; 27 items
  - McConahy, John G. -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1981 October 16; 1 item
  - McCormack, Mike, 1972-1976; 2 items
  - McNamee, George C. -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1986 June 24; 1 item
  - Mekhon Vaitsman le-mada., 1972-1977; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1972; 7 items
    - Folder 2, 1973-1977; 16 items
  - Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center, 1963-1986; 6 folders
    - Folder 1, 1963-1970; 54 items
    - Folder 2, 1971-1972; 33 items
    - Folder 3, 1973; 23 items
    - Folder 4, 1974-1982; 44 items
    - Folder 5, 1983-1984; 34 items
    - Folder 6, 1985-1986; 16 items
  - Meselson, Matthew, 1985; 3 items
  - METRO, New York Metropolitan Reference and Research Library, 1981-1986; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1981-1982; 12 items
    - Folder 2, 1983-1986; 15 items
  - Meyer, Carl H., 1985; 3 items
  - Mikesell, Nancy, 1977; 2 items
  - Milton Roy Company -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1982 March 31; 1 item
  - Ming-teh, Li, 1979; 2 items
  - Miscellaneous, n.d.; 7 items
  - Mott, N. F. (Nevill Francis), Sir, 1905-, 1977; 2 items
  - Moynihan, Daniel P. (Daniel Patrick), 1927- -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1984 January 12; 1 item
  - Montedison Progetto Cultura, 1986; 3 items
  - NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund, 1975-1986; 4 items
  - Naftalin, Micah H., 1982; 4 items
  - National Academy of Engineering, 1966-1986; 8 folders
    - Folder 1, 1966-1967; 44 items
    - Folder 2, 1968-1971; 30 items
    - Folder 3, 1972-1974; 29 items
    - Folder 4, 1975-1976; 27 items
    - Folder 5, 1977-1979; 19 items
    - Folder 6, 1981-1982; 45 items
    - Folder 7, 1983-1986; 44 items
    - Awards -- Folder 8, 1968-1970; 41 items
  - National Academy of Public Administration, 1981-1982; 7 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.), 1963-1985; 26 folders
    - Folder 1, 1963; 112 items
      Letters of congratulations on election to NAS.
    - Folder 2, 1971 January-March; 60 items
    - Folder 3, 1971 April-July; 59 items
    - Folder 4, 1971 September-December; 45 items
    - Folder 5, 1972 January-May; 30 items
    - Folder 6, 1972 June-September; 25 items
    - Folder 7, 1972 October-December; 42 items
    - Folder 8, 1973 January-September; 10 items
    - Folder 9, 1973 October-December; 20 items
    - Folder 10, 1974; 41 items
    - Folder 11, 1975 January-May; 31 items
    - Folder 12, 1975 June-December; 52 items
    - Folder 13, 1976 January-July; 43 items
    - Folder 14, 1976 August-December; 59 items
    - Folder 15, 1977 January-February; 49 items
    - Folder 16, 1977 May-August; 52 items
    - Folder 17, 1977 September-December; 25 items
    - Folder 18, 1978; 31 items
    - Folder 19, 1979; 35 items
    - Folder 20, 1980 January; 13 items
    - Folder 21, 1980 February-March; 24 items
    - Folder 22, 1980 April-May; 12 items
    - Folder 23, 1980 September-December; 14 items
    - Folder 24, 1981; 15 items
    - Folder 25, 1982-1983; 11 items
    - Folder 26, 1984-1985; 17 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Awards and Grants, 1979-1980; 12 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Computer Science and Engineering Board, 1968-1971; 44 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Council, 1973-1976; 35 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Cyrus B. Comstock Fund, 1965-1970; 22 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Gomory Committee, 1979; 6 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Institute of Medicine (U.S.), 1973-1974; 4 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Invitations, 1963; 14 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Navy Study, 1974-1975; 31 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Nominations, 1968; 5 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Physics Survey Committee, 1969-1971; 4 folders
    - Folder 1, 1969; 19 items
    - Folder 2, 1970; 29 items
    - Folder 3, 1971; 6 items
    - Folder 4, 1971; 33 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Public Welfare Medal, 1968-1970; 46 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Quissett Property, 1976; 6 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- Travel, 1960-1971; 29 items
  - National Academy of Sciences (U.S.) -- White, Gilbert F., 1972-1975; 17 items
  - National Association of Science Writers, inc. -- TLS to Piore, Emanual Ruben, 1908-2000, 1972 December 13; 1 item
  - National Commission on Research, n.d.; 2 items
  - National Information Bureau, 1975 November 11; 1 item
  - National Institutes of Health (U.S.), 1965-1975; 7 items
  - National Medal of Science, 1962-1974; 76 items
    - Folder 1, 1962-1967; 35 items
    - Folder 2, 1968-1974; 30 items
  - National Research Corps, 1946-1947; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1946; 41 items
    - Folder 2, 1947; 17 items
  - National Research Council (U.S.), 1975-1985; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1975-1977; 18 items
    - Folder 2, 1978; 43 items
    - Folder 3, 1980-1985; 14 items
  - National Science Board (U.S.), 1961-1974; 35 items
    Three group photographs included. Removed to Series V.
  - National Science Board (U.S.) -- Long Range Planning Committee, 1969-1973; 4 folders
    - Folder 1, 1969; 16 items
    - Folder 2, 1970; 14 items
    - Folder 3, 1970; 14 items
    - Folder 4, 1971-1973; 17 items
  - National Science Board (U.S.) -- Travel, 1959-1971; 119
  - National Science Foundation (U.S.), 1970-1984; 23 items
  - National Science Foundation (U.S.) -- The National Science Board and The Formulation of National Science Policy, 1981 July 31; 2 items
  - Naval Historical Foundation, 1982; 5 items
  - Naval Research Advisory Committee, 1973-1985; 18 items
  - Nerken, Albert, 1977; 5 items
  - Neuberger, Roy, 1979; 3 items
  - Neufeld, Maurice F. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 December 20; 1 item
  - Neugebauer, Gerry, 1932-, n.d.; 1 item
  - Neurosciences Institute (La Jolla, San Diego, Calif.), 1982; 2 items
  - Newcomen Society in North America, 1965-1971; 20 items
  - The New Leader, 1975; 2 items
  - Newman, Edward -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1973 January 18; 1 item
  - Newspaper clippings, 1961; 3 items
  - The Newtown Fund, 1985; 3 items
  - New York, 1976-1985; 10 items
  - New York Academy of Sciences, 1975; 3 items
  - New York City Science and Technology Advisory Council, 1965 -1971; 25 items
  - The New Yorker, 1969-1971; 6 items
  - New York Hall of Science, 1967-1986; 31 folders
    - Folder 1, 1967; 39 items
    - Folder 2, 1972; 27 items
    - Folder 3, 1973; 13 items
    - Folder 4, 1973; 10 items
    - Folder 5, 1974; 19 items
    - Folder 6, 1974; 25 items
    - Folder 7, 1975; 16 items
    - Folder 8, 1976; 21 items
    - Folder 9, 1977; 27 items
    - Folder 10, 1978; 35 items
    - Folder 11, 1978; 7 items
    - Folder 12, 1979; 11 items
    - Folder 13, 1980; 23 items
    - Folder 14, 1980; 23 items
    - Folder 15, 1981; 21 items
    - Folder 16, 1981; 26 items
    - Folder 17, 1981; 29 items
    - Folder 18, 1982; 34 items
    - Folder 19, 1982; 26 items
    - Folder 20, 1982; 12 items
    - Folder 21, 1983; 25 items
    - Folder 22, 1983; 12 items
    - Folder 23, 1984; 12 items
    - Folder 24, 1984; 33 items
    - Folder 25, 1984; 12 items
    - Folder 26, 1985; 12 items
    - Folder 27, 1985; 11 items
      Studio photograph of Piore smoking pipe included. Removed to Series V.
    - Folder 28, 1985; 13 items
    - Folder 29, 1985; 10 items
    - Folder 30, 1986; 12 items
    - Folder 31, 1986; 28 items
  - New York Hall of Science -- Proposal to the National Science Foundation, 1973; 3 items
  - New York State Bar Association, 1969-1970; 8 items
  - New York State Project 2000, 1986; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1986; items
    - Folder 2, 1986; 15 items
  - New York State Science and Technology Foundation, 1964-1985; 13 folders
    - Folder 1, 1964-1971; 27 items
    - Folder 2, 1974-1975; 20 items
    - Folder 3, 1976; 15 items
    - Folder 4, 1977; 14 items
    - Folder 5, 1978; 13 items
    - Folder 6, 1979; 18 items
    - Folder 7, 1979; 11 items
    - Folder 8, 1980; 14 items
    - Folder 9, 1981; 7 items
    - Folder 10, 1981; 10 items
    - Folder 11, 1981; 10 items
    - Folder 12, 1982; 6 items
    - Folder 13, 1983-1985; 23 items
  - New York State Science and Technology Foundation -- Board of Directors Meeting, 29 September 1980, 6 items
  - New York State Science and Technology Foundation -- Board of Directors Meeting, 1 May 1984, 1 item
  - New York University, 1981; 2 items
  - New York University -- Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, 1958-1986; 4 folders
    - Folder 1, 1958-1972; 20 items
    - Folder 2, 1973-1979; 17 items
    - Folder 3, 1980-1982; 16 items
    - Folder 4, 1983-1986; 25 items
  - Nierenberg, William Aaron, 1919-, 1983-1984; 4 items
  - Nishina, Yuichiro, 1930-, 1983; 2 items
  - Niven, David, 1910-, 1 item
  - Nixon, Sir Edwin, 1985; 2 items
  - Nobel, Alfred Bernhard, 1833-1896, n.d.; 1 item
  - Nobel festival, 1973-1975; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 21 items
    - Folder 2, 27 items
  - North Carolina, 1978; 2 items
  - North Carolina State University, 1985-1986; 20 items
  - Nye, Larry -- TLS Cy to Gentlemen, 1975 June 7; 1 item
  - Nyquist, Ewald B., 1914-, 1976; 2 items
  - O'Connor, Joe, 1982; 2 items
  - Oettinger, Anthony G., 1973-1974; 3 items
  - Ogden, Alfred, 1979; 2 items
  - O.K. Industries, inc., 1979 December 31; 1 item
  - Old, Bruce S., 1979-1982; 3 items
  - Old, Lloyd J. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1978 April 29; 1 item
  - Onek, David, 1982; 2 items
  - Onek, Joseph, 1971-1982; 8 items
  - Onek, Matt -- ALS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, n.d.; 1 item
  - Opel, John -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 December 29; 2 items
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1904-1967, 1963-1977; 2 items
  - Onoyama, Hiroko, 1981; 2 items
  - Ormond Corp., 1982; 3 items
  - Ovrut, Susan, 1951-, 1983; 2 items
  - Packard, David, 1976-1986; 2 items
  - Pake, G. E. (George Edward), 1976; 2 items
  - Palmer, Ralph L. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1983 March 30; 1 item
  - Panofsky, Wolfgang Kurt Hermann, 1919-, 1979-1980; 11 items
  - Paul Revere Investors, inc., 1971-1983; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1971; 22 items
    - Folder 2, 1976-1983; 26 items
  - Penick, Joseph E., 1983; 2 items
  - Pettit, Joseph M. (Joseph Mayo), 1986; 2 items
  - Pfeiffer, Jane, 1978; 2 items
  - Pfeiffer, Ralph A., 1977-1978; 2 items
  - Phi Beta Kappa Associates, 1972-1983; 2 items
  - Phillips, Ethel -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1982 July 14; 1 item
  - Philosophical Society of Washington, Washington, D.C., 1951-1969; 10 items
  - Physics Emigrant Fund -- TL to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1974 March 31; 1 item
  - Physics Today, 1976-1983; 7 items
  - Piccone, Dan N., 1973; 3 items
  - Picker, Harvey, 1983; 2 items
  - Pickering, William Hayward, 1910-, 1976; 3 items
  - Piel, Gerard, 1981-1982; 3 items
  - Piel, Jonathan, 1981; 2 items
  - Pierce, John Robinson, 1910-, 1977; 7 items
  - Pifer, Alan, 1972; 2 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Anniversary, 1968 July 20; 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Awards, 1930-1979; 8 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Biographical Material, 4 folders
    - Folder 1, 1973; 14 items
    - Folder 2, 1972-1975; 8 items
    - Autobiographical material -- Folder 3, 1975-1984; 8 items
    - Miscellaneous notes -- Folder 4, 19 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Chilmark House addition (Martha's Vineyard), 1970; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1970; 41 items
    - Folder 2, 1970; 30 items
    - Folder 3, 1970; 57 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Chilmark House correspondence (Martha's Vineyard), 1962-1966; 26 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Chilmark House Paid Bills (Martha's Vineyard), 1971; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1971; 61 items
    - Folder 2, 1971; 51 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Computer-Present and Future: Intoduction to the Symposium, 1980; 1 item
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- The Department of Science, 1985; 2 items
  - [Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000] -- Detlev Wolf Bronk: The Transition from War to Peace, 1976; 2 items
    Included photograph of Bronk. Original removed to series V.
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Government Boards and Commitees, 10 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Interview, 1965; 2 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Latern Slides, 1969; 3 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Medical Benefits, 1970-1971; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1970; 44 items
    - Folder 2, 1971; 55 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- National Science Policy, 1980; 9 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Notes, 1981-1982; 5 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Office of Navel Research the first ten years: A Summary, 1977; 4 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Personnel Papers, 1942-1969; 6 folders
    - Folder 1, 1942-1945; 17 items
    - Folder 2, 1946-1949; 28 items
    - Folder 3, 1950-1953; 32 items
    - Folder 4, 1955-1957; 35 items
    - Folder 5, 1960-1964; 10 items
    - Folder 6, 1967-1969; 24 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Publicity, 1954-1967; 5 folders
    - Folder 1, 1945-1955; 17 items
    - Folder 2, 1956; 18 items
    - Folder 3, 1958; 2 items
    - Folder 4, 1959; 30 items
    - Folder 5, 1960-1967; 19 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Research in Industry, 2 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Retirement letters, 1971-1972; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1971; 34 items
    - Folder 2, 1971; 26 items
    - Folder 3, 1972; 42 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Science, Public Policy and related notes, 1975-1980; 15 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- The Scientist in the White House: A Sociological View, 1979; 5 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Subscriptions, 1971-1972; 17 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Testimony before the Kennedy Committee, 1975; 9 items13 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Thougths, miscellaneous, n.d.; 2 items
  - Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000 -- Travel, 1982; 2 items
  - Piore, Jane, 1945-, 2 items
  - Piore, Margot, 1942-, 2 items
  - Piore, Michael J., 1959-1882; 15 items
  - Piore, Nancy -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1974 June 24; 1 item
  - Piore, Nora, 1933-1946; 2 items
  - Platt, Joseph, 1976-1981; 6 items
  - The Plaza, 1973; 2 items
  - PMC/BETA corporation, 1981 July 31; 1 item
  - Polk, Robert L., 1980; 3 items
  - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn., 1962-1980; 38 items
  - Powers, Linda S., 1985; 6 items
  - Pratt, Richardson, 1977; 2 items
  - President's Science Advisory Committee, 1958-1973; 9 folders
    - Folder 1, 1958-1959; 7 items
    - Folder 2, 1960-1964; 26 items
    - Folder 3, 1965-1967; 17 items
    - Folder 4, 1969-1970; 22 items
    - Folder 5, 1971; 21 items
    - Folder 6, 1971; 14 items
    - Folder 7, 1972; 15 items
    - Folder 8, 1972; 19 items
    - Folder 9, 1973; 17 items
  - President's Science Advisory Committee -- Panel on Government Laboratories, 1964-1965; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1964; 16 items
    - Folder 2, 1964; 16 items
    - Folder 3, 1965; 15 items
  - Press, Frank, 1977-1980; 8 items
  - Princeton University -- ALS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1980 January 2; 1 item
  - Proebster, W. E. -- TLS to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1985 June 24; 1 item
  - Public Benefits of the Arts and Humanities, 1984; 2 items
  - Pyne, Eben W., 1976; 2 items
  - Quadri Corporation, 1970-1984; 2 items
  - Rabi, I. I. (Isidor Isaac), 1898-, 1973-1981; 8 items
  - Rabin, Michael, 1975; 2 items
  - Rabinow, Jacob, 1976; 2 items
  - Ramo, Simon -- TL Cy to Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1980 January 23; 1 item
  - Rand Corporation, 1973; 4 items
  - Rees, Mina Spiegel, 1902-, 1979-1983; 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1979; 8 items
    - Folder 2, 1981; 26 items
    - Folder 3, 1982-1983; 22 items
  - Rees, Mina Spiegel, 1902- -- Math in WWII, n.d.; 1 item
  - Rennebaum, R. B. -- TL Cy from Piore, Emanuel Ruben, 1908-2000, 1977 December 21; 1 item
  - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, 1984; 2 items
  - Report of the National Academy of Sciences' Site Evaluation -- TMs, 1966 March; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1966 March; 44 p.
    - Folder 2, 1966 March; 46 p.
  - Reprints, 1974-1982; 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1974-1979; 3 items
    - Folder 2, 1980-1982; 3 items
  - Research Corporation, 1973; 3 items
  - Research and Science Investors, inc., 1966-1984; 8 folders
    - Folder 1, 1966-1967; 7 items
    - Folder 2, 1968-1969; 23 items
    - Folder 3, 1970; 7 items
    - Folder 4, 1971; 13 items
    - Folder 5, 1972; 21 items
    - Folder 6, 1974-1975; 14 items
    - Folder 7, 1976-1978; 12 items
    - Folder 8, 1980-1984; 7 items
  - Resources for the Future, 1969-1978; 2 Folder
    - Folder 1, 1969-1970; 6 items
    - Folder 2, 1971-1978; 23 items